In the previous video,
在上一个视频中
you saw two methods for how we might choose between competing hypotheses.
你学习了在对立的假设中进行选择的两种方法
In the second method,
在第二种方法中
we ask the question if the null hypothesis is true,
我们问了一个问题 如果零假设为真
what is the probability of obtaining the statistic we observed in
获得数据中观察到的统计量或者更极端统计量
our data or one more extreme in favor of the alternative hypothesis?
从而选择对立假设的概率是多少？
This probability is what is called a P-value.
这个概率称为 P 值
Finding the P-value involves a mix of ideas that you've learned about,
P 值的确定涉及你学到的多个概念
sampling distributions and conditional probability.
抽样分布和条件概率
Imagine we have a null that a population mean is equal to zero.
假如我们有一个零假设 假设总体均值等于零
Then we collect sample data and we find the sample mean
我们收集样本数据 发现样本均值
to be five and the sample standard deviation to be two.
是五 样本标准偏差是二
Assuming the sampling distribution of your statistic follows the null hypothesis.
假设统计量的抽样分布符合零假设
What is the probability of observing
从这个分布中的数据
the actual value of the statistic from your data in this distribution?
观察到统计量实际值的概率是多少？
If we want to know the probability that
如果我们想知道
the population mean is actually greater than zero,
总体均值实际大于零的概率
you could update the hypothesis.
你可以更新假设
Values like 6, 7,
6、7、10
10 all fall out here and are even more of an indication that the alternative is true,
等值都在这 更像是表明对立假设为真
that our population mean is greater than zero.
总体均值大于零
Additionally, what is the probability you observed
另外 观察到的统计量
something even more in favor of the alternative hypothesis?
表明需要选择对立假设的概率是多少？
This shaded region here provides that probability, the P-value.
这个阴影区域就是这个概率 也就是 P 值
Notice the P-value is dependent on
注意 P 值取决于
your alternative hypothesis as it determines what is considered more extreme.
对立假设 因为它决定了更极端的值
If your alternative hypothesis is that your parameter is greater than zero,
如果对立假设是参数大于零
then we shade greater than the statistic as shown here.
阴影区域会比现在显示的统计量大
However, if we change our null and alternative to look like this,
但是 如果我们把零假设和对立假设改成这样
then we shade to the left of our statistic.
阴影区域应该在这个统计量左边
Our shading for the P-value would now look like this.
P 值的阴影区域现在是这样
Notice that this would create a very large probability in
注意 这会形成非常大的概率
this case as almost the entire distribution is shaded.
因为这种情况下 几乎整个分布区域都是阴影
And if you have a not equal sign in the alternative,
如果对立假设中含有不等关系
then your shading is associated with extremes that
阴影区域则与在两个方向
are just far from the null in either direction.
均远离零假设的极端值相关
In these cases, we just care about
这种情况下 我们只关心
statistics that are far from the null in either direction.
在两个方向均远离零假设的统计量
So we end up marking on both sides and
所以我们最终在远离零假设的
shading away from the null hypothesis to find our P-value.
两端涂阴影 从而确定 P 值
This often takes people a while to wrap their heads around.
要弄明白这个 需要一些时间
And there are two parts to understand.
要理解的有两个部分
First, you have to fully conceptualize the definition of a P-value,
第一 你必须把 P 值完全概念化
which is the conditional probability of your data given that the null hypothesis is true.
它是零假设为真的情况下数据的条件概率
Then, you need to figure out what to compute,
然后 你需要明白要计算的是什么
which is visually summarized by these three images.
这三个图片有很直观的总结
You will get some practice with both of these before moving
在开始学习运用 P 值的概念做决策之前
on and applying the ideas of P-value to make decisions.
你还需要对这两个部分进行练习